Hailing from Guberland, Gawain "Nutty" Nurtigan is famed not only for his many "romantic" exploits, but also for his valiant prowess on the field of battle. This warring explorer's strong arm is matched only - naturally enough - by his foolhardy bravado. Nurtigan acted as a de facto leader of Guberland's survivors following the island clan's invasion from the Mendossian armada, fighting alongside the kindhearted Lord Maine Arran during the recent unification of Framon. Since the Lord's unfortunate poisoning, Gawain has served his daughter, Queen Iona, his loyalty always a valuable asset to Framon's people.