Born into one of AvLee's noble families, it was Harke's fate to join the Elven Court and maybe one day lead the elven people. When he entered the Forest Guard, however, he found he loved the intricacies of battle and remained one of its commanders for far longer than anyone would have expected. Even if most of his former abilities are useless now that he is living among the A'Rikdun clan in their subterrean domain, he remains a skilled ranger.