The Dragons work in mysterious ways, and Guruthos is no exception. Older than the Ancients' Silence, this wyrm is credited with the destruction of Askhelion (Axeoth's first knight), siding with the Kreegan Vanguard in their original attack for knowledge and technological power. Ultimately desiring to rule the world for himself in the Ancients' absence, Guruthos was, alas, no match for Escaton the Destroyer. Trapped in the Tomb of a Thousand Terrors alongside his tentative allies, Guruthos has recently been released, resuming his forgotten ambitions. His sole known weakness is the spear of the long-dead Askhelion himself.