The self-styled Defender of the Land, Nicolai is the son of Roland and Catherine Ironfist, the rulers of Enroth and Erathia prior to the destruction wrought by the Reckoning. Finding himself in Axeoth following the collapse of Castle Ironfist, Nicolai has remained vigilant of the Kreegan menace since his fateful arrival in this distant realm. In spite of his ever-perilous circumstances, the hapless "king" nonetheless shows an unlikely ability to escape danger at every turn. Those among Rysh's more superstitious populace can only assume that he has been marked by the Gods themselves.