The dwarf known as Crag Hack (who bears no relation to the human barbarian sharing his nickname) was born on a distant world called Terra. On his homeworld, he fought alongside his friends against the mad Guardian, Sheltem, a fight that eventually led him to the world of Enroth. There he became an advisor of the kingdom of Bracada during the Occult War, before embarking with both old and new companions upon a new quest : to find the mysterious Ancients. After years of exploring the worlds of the Spinward Rim looking for them (unsuccessfully), Crag Hack felt it was time for him to part ways with his brothers in arms and return back to Terra to spend the rest of his life with his family. Unfortunately, an accident while manipulating the Ancients' portals sent him to Axeoth, where he has lived ever since.