Imbued with the mightiest mystical powers of the Kreegans, the Armageddon's Blade is able to disrupt the balance between the four elements, opening a rift to the realm of fire. Even if the blade broke during the Last Battle, when it destroyed the world of Enroth, it still wields tremendous powers. Adds +3 to the Hero's Attack and Spellpower, but the tragic history of the blade gives a penalty of -2 to Morale.