Ruthless in combat, compassionate in the throne room and well-respected by both friend and foe, the infamous Sven "Forkbeard" Svenssen has literally been to death and back, having led the united Chedian armies against foreign hordes under the Beldonian warlord, Tamur Leng, a few years past. His rulership of Thjorgard renders him one of Rysh's most powerful men alive to this day, matched only by the power-hungry conquerering forces of nearby nations such as Channon, Beldonia and Mendossus - tyrants this worldly Jarl comprehends only too well, having dealt with more than a few in person.