The sil of menkar is known among the A'Rikdun clan to be more interested in hedonistic pleasures than the well-being of the clan. Pryden grew disgusted with the ways of his family. Taking interest in all aspects of the political life of the clan, he studied tirelessly to become a competent leader for his sil. But Pryden is one driven by anger and after restoring the honor and respect of his own family, he needed a new subject of hatred. That's when he learned about the arrival of the Exiled... Some say all Pryden's doings are actually aimed at impressing his childhood friend Thalia a'deneb. But so far he has failed to prove himself anything more than a foolish, stubborn idiot to her. 