Armed with a deathless determination and a host of trusted, noble allies, the young Queen Iona Arran has asserted herself against the odds as a fine successor for her late father, Lord Maine Arran of Framon. With the aid of Gawain Nurtigan, her loyal advisor and close friend, she has almost single-handedly secured peace and unity among Framon's people, never relenting in her efforts to strengthen and support this battle-weary nation against any who would bring it strife. Though still among Axeoth's youngest fully-fledged rulers, Iona is neither foolish nor easily manipulated, a few of the many traits which shaped her into a leader her people can truly pride themselves upon.