Archibald was once the “bad seed” of the Ironfist family, who fought against his brother Roland for the throne of Enroth. Taking control of the necromancers of Deyja after the final death of Nicolas Gryphonheart, he was forced to abdicate after a coup d’état from one of his advisers. Having survived the Reckoning, Archibald understood he had been offered a second chance to do some good in his life.