The sil of menkar is known among the A'Rikdun clan to be more interested in hedonistic pleasures than the well-being of the clan. Pryden grew up disgusted by the ways of his family. Taking interest into all the aspects of the political life of the clan, he studied tirelessly to become a competent leader for his sil. But Pryden is one driven by anger and after restoring the honor and respect of his own family, he needed a new subject of hatred. That's when he learned about the arrival of the Exiled... Some say all Pryden's doing is actually to impress his childhood friend Thalia a'deneb. But so far he has failed to prove himself anything else than a nice, stubborn idiot to her.