Skraelos is the God of Death, and the Gatekeeper of both Hallenhalt and the Underworld. He is the one who judges the souls of the dead, and it is he who deems them unworthy to go to Hallenhalt. According to folklore, he imposes trials on those seeking rebirth, and reincarnates them if they succeed. He is by far the most mysterious of the Gods, but is often presented as a benevolent, compassionate being. He is an avatar of the Force of the Dome known as Lurkane by the Ancients.